Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: [P-WCM] Published Material by WCM, (3 Boxes: Boxes 38-40)
  - "Money and Credit in the Recovery Program, Introduction" (1 copy). (Box 39)
  - "Money and Foreign Exchange after 1914" (3 copies). (Box 39)
  - "National Bureau*s L'easures cf Cyclical Eehavior" (1 copy). (Box 39)
  - "National Unity and Individual Liberties" (4 copies). (Box 39)
  - "New Banking Measure in the United States" (1 copy). (Box 39)
  - "New Gold and the Fall of Prices" (1 copy). (Box 39)
  - "Introduction to Our Changing Social Order" (8 copies). (Box 39)
  - Foreword to Essays in Social Economics in Honor of Jessica Elanche Peixotto (6 copies). (Box 39)
  - Review of J. Peixotto's Getting and Spending at the Professional Standard of Living (5 copies). (Box 39)
  - "Prices and Reconstruction" (1 copy). (Box 39)
  - Public Relations of Science" (47 copies). (Box 39)
  - "Rationality Econosdc Activity" (1 copy). (Box 40)
  - "Real Issues - in the Quantity Theory Controversy" (1 copy). (Box 40)
  - "Research Fellowships of the Social Science Research Council" (2 copies). (Box 40)
  - Reviews of: (Box 40)
  - M. Prager's Die Yi'ahrungs Bankrefora in den Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika. (Box 40)
  - G. Peedrs Valics or the Science of Values. (Box 40)
  - J. Curren's Francis A. Walker und seine Hauptsachlichsten Theorien. (Box 40)
  - C. Steinbruck's Die Entwicklung der Preise des Stadtischen; und Ländichen Immobiliarbesitzes zu Halle und im Saalkreise (Box 40)
  - I. DrenkoffTs Die Steuerverhaltnisse Bulgariens. (Box 40)
  - Demuth's Th. v. Bernhardi: ein Beitrag zur Geschichte der Nationalokonogiie. (1 copy). (Box 40)
  - "Robbins, The Great Depression" (4 copies). (Box 40)
  - Review of D. E. Robertson's A Study of Industrial Fluctuation. (Box 40)
  - Role of Money in Economic History" (15 copies) (Box 40)
  - The Role of Money in Economic Theory" (a copy) (Box 40)
  - "Role of Research in Economic Progress" (1 copy) (Box 40)
  - "Henry Rogers Seager: 1870-1930" (5 copies). (Box 40)
  - "Edwin Robert Anderson Seligman, 1861-l939 (13 copies) (Box 40)
  - Review of H. Sewall’s Theory of Value before Adam Smith (1 copy) (Box 40)
  - "Science and the State of Mind"; Spanish translation (1 copy). (Box 40)
  - "Sombart’s Hochkapitalisaus" (1 copy). (Box 40)
  - "Statistics and Government" (2 copies). (Box 40)
  - Review of W. Taylor's Credit System (1 copy). (Box 40)
  - "Thorstein Veblen, 1857-1929" (4 copies). (Box 40)
  - "War prices in the United States" (1 copy) (Box 40)
  - "Allyn Abbott Young" (1 copy) (Box 40)
  - Review of R. Zon and W. Sparhawk's Forest Resources of the World. (Box 40)
- Series VI: [M] Money, The Money Economy, and Economic History, (2 Boxes: Boxes 34 and 35)
  - 1902 Apr 18; hol 1 p; examination; EH. (Box 34)
  - 1902 [May ?]; hol 1 p; EH; examination. (Box 34)
  - 1902 [?]; hol 1 p; EH; assignments. (Box 34)
  - [1908 ?] hol 2p.; M; course outline (Box 34, Folder M34)
  - [1908 ?] hol 2p; M; course outline (Box 34, Folder M187)
  - [1908 ?]; printed 14 p; bibliography - on money and monetary history and prices; from Harvard. (Box 34, Folder M28)
  - [?]; hol 1 p; M; class assignments (Box 34, Folder M30)
  - [?]; printed 4 p; bibliography on American economic history [from Harvard?] (Box 34, Folder M124)
  - [1908 ?]; M: (Box 34, Folder M35)
  - Course plans (Box 34)
  - Development of monetary systems - ancient and medieval (Box 34)
  - Coinage history (Box 34)
  - 16th century gold inflow (Box 34)
  - Statistics (Box 34)
  - England and gold standard (Box 34)
  - Banking origins (Box 34)
  - Colonial systems (Box 34)
  - American monetary development - Revolution, Hamilton, U.S. 1801-47 (Box 34)
  - Sherman Act and panic of 1893 (Box 34)
  - U.S. 1894-1907 (Box 34)
  - European development to 1848 (Box 34)
  - U.S. and European developments 1848-70 and 1871-93 (Box 34)
  - Attached: gold (Box 34)
  - Production statistics (Box 34)
  - Quote by I. Hurwick on silver. (Box 34)
  - 1909 Aug - Dec; hol 1 p; M; class readings. (Box 34)
  - 1909 Nov 19-Dec 6; hol 2 p; M; money and prices. (Box 34)
  - 1916 May 8; hol 1 p; course lecture notes: Marshall on money. (Box 34)
  - 1917 Jan 10; hol 2 p; Tp; 26th lecture; Marshall on money (used 1/17/17). (Box 34)
  - 1917 Jan 15; hol 1 p; Tp; Marshall on money (used l/l7/l7). (Box 34)
  - 1920 Jan 10; hol & carbon ms 5 p; "Growth of the Modern Factory System"; Talk to joint Board of Sanitary Control, New York City. (Box 34)
  - 1920 Nov 23; hol 2 p; "Economic Organization and the Trade Union"; 2d lecture. (Box 34)
  - 1922 Dec 26; carbon 7 p; discussion of J.C. Trautwine on WCM "Making Goods and Making Money" (Box 34)
  - 1923 Jan 28; carbon ms; 5 p; "Uses Made of Honey and Leisure; suggestions for a Series of Investigations". (Box 34)
  - 1923 Nov 7; carbon ms 2 p; copy 2 p; review of A. Monroe's Monetary Theory before Adam Smith (published as "History of Theories"). (Box 34)
  - 1923 Dec 15; carbon ms 6 p; "Preamble to the Plan of the National Monetary Association"; revision of draft written by Rovensky and Hastings. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Feb 4; hol 5 p; ME; 1st lecture; course plans. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Feb 9; hol 3 p; ME; money in antiquity and among aborigines, institutions; assignments. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Feb 11; hol 1 p; ME; money in social behavior. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Feb 15-16; hol & typed 22 p; ME; students’ suggestions for seminar papers; by: J. Cornell, A. Achenstein, A. Pellman, D. McConnell, W. Kim, E. Taylor, M. Gilson [?], R. Jadoul, L. McMorris, P. Lean [?], H. Slade, S. Kuznets, I. Allen, J. Bane [?], H. Taylor, Cuttrell, R. Roby. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Peb 16; hol 2 p; ME; money and social behavior; social sciences, habits. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Feb 18;hol 5 p; ME; institutions in social life and their formation, habits, change. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Feb 23; hol 1 p; ME; assignments. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Mar 11; hol 1 p; ME; development of money economy. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Mar 16; hol 5 p; ME; money economy and production and distribution, efficiency, invention and diffusion. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Mar 18; hol 6 p; ME; evolution of money economy, cumulative process, inventions. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Kar 23 [& later]; hol 14 p; HE; evolution of money econony, economics and money economy - non causal science of behavior, classical economics and utility economics and money economy, statistical empirical work, summary and suggestions. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 4, 11, May 6; hol 3 p; ME; criticisms of money economy technical and welfare, consumers, use of netcresources. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 8; hol 4 p; ME; making and spending money, economic organizataion, business enterprise. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 13, 15; hol 6 p; ME; interdependence of businesses, system of prices, role of prices, money mechanism, equation of exchange and business psychology (used 4/8/26). (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 20; hol 3 p; ME; equation of exchange, secular price movements (used 4/15/26). (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 22; hol 3 p; ME; flow of money payments - income, business spendings, savings; guidance of economic activity, uncertainty (used 4/27/26). (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 27; hol 3 p; ME; business management and guidance - big business structure, technical advisors, lenders, consumers. (Box 34)
  - 1926 Apr 29; hol 5 p; guidance - consumers, government, planlessness; money economy and production intereference - bankers, businessmen, farmers (G.Warren, H.L. Moore), war, foreign trade; overproduction, money economy and prices (used 4/27/26). (Box 34)
  - 1926 May 4; hol 5 p; ME; production limitation, overproduction, Pollak theory, disturbances in money econony (used 5/6/26). (Box 34)
  - 1926 May 6; hol 4 p; ME; overproduction, price determination, statistics, criticisms of money economy. (Box 34)
  - 1926 May 11; hol 2 p; ME; summary and results, money econony and economic theory. (Box 34)
  - 1926 May 13; hol 7 p; ME; behavior study and theory (used 5/11/26). (Box 34)
  - 1937 Jan 14; see 1/14/37A (Box 34)
  - 1937 Apr 22; hol 1 p; Seminar; functions of the enterprises. (Box 34)
  - 1937 Fall; see Fall 1937 A. (Box 34)
  - 1939 May 23; hol 6 p; Economic Theory Seminar; summary on imperialism. (Box 34)
  - 1939 Oct 5; hol 16 p; "Money and Economic Activities"; lecture to Columbia banking seminar (Box 34)
  - 1941 Jan 6-Mar 31; hol 1 p; Economic Theory Seminar; assignments - seminar history of economic organisation. (Box 34)
  - 1941 Mar 31; hol. 8 p; Seminar; money and economic behavior - summary of historical and analytical reports by class members. (Box 34)
  - 1944 Sep 30; typed Us 11 p; copy 11 p; "Role of Money in Economic History"; talk to Economic History Association session; attached program and meeting information. undated notes (before 1913) (Box 34)
  - Hol 3 p; price level changes and gold standard. (Box 34, Folder M22)
  - Hol 3 p; money in U.S., 1907. (Box 34, Folder M23)
  - Hol 5 p; foreign monetary systems. (Box 34, Folder M24)
  - Hol 12 p; gold exchange standard in Philippines. (Box 34, Folder M25)
  - Hol 2 p; gold exchange standard in Panama. (Box 34, Folder M26)
  - Printed 8 p; table: -world gold and silver output 1893-1904. (Box 34, Folder M27)
  - Hol 61 p: tables: paper money in Austria. (Box 34, Folder M31)
  - [After 1906]; hol 9 p; money and price level changes, gold standard. (Box 34, Folder M32)
  - Hol 7 p; gold standard in Mexico; attached- 2 clippings. (Box 34, Folder H36)
  - Hol 3 p; changes in price level. (Box 34, Folder M37)
  - Hol 1 p; price level changes. (Box 34, Folder M33)
  - Hol 1 p; monetary demand for gold, gold and price level. (Box 34, Folder M47)
  - Hol 3 p; business capital and price level. (Box 34, Folder M45)
  - Hol 2 p; low prices - wholesalers and manufacturers. (Box 34, Folder M39)
  - [1908 ?]; hol 64 p; role of prices, system of prices, money making, price system and wants, pecuniary viewpoint, technical exigencies, development of price systems and changes, index numbers, quantity theory, Laughlin, price making process, money and price level changes, gold production and stocks and demand; class assignments. (Box 34, Folder M46)
  - Hol 1 p; money economy and price system. (Box 34, Folder M49)
  - hol 6 p; M; monetary systems - U.S., evolution of, significance of money economy and leading features, price system, price statistics. (Box 34, Folder M48)
  - Hol 1 p; assignments - price statistics. (Box 34, Folder M50)
  - [1908 ?]; hol 16 p; monetary system of the U.S. - currency elasticity, gold standard, Inquiry of 1896 attached - statistics, Fisher's velocity estimates. (Box 34, Folder M1151)
  - Hol 1 p; E0; economic life of - ancient Egypt, Mesopotamia, Greece, Rome. (Box 34, Folder M170)
  - Hol 8 p; EO; Mesopotamia. (Box 34, Folder M171)
  - Hol 1 p; Merovingian’s’ gold and silver supply. (Box 34, Folder M176)
  - Hol 3 p; EH; course plans. (Box 34, Folder M172)
  - Hol 1 p; money economy in Middle Ages - Florence. (Box 34, Folder M175)
  - hol 15 p; EH; 1st lecture; course plans, readings (ethnology and history) (Box 34, Folder M173)
  - Hol 1 p; difficulties of coinage in Middle Ages. (Box 34, Folder M331)
  - Hol 1 p; EH; dates of reigns of English kings, 1066-1603. (Box 34, Folder M116)
  - Hol 13 p; EH; manorial system before 1056 in England. (Box 34, Folder M120)
  - Hol 17 p; towns in the Saxon period. (Box 34, Folder M117)
  - Hol 7 p; EH; town life after 1066 in England. (Box 34, Folder M122)
  - Hol p; finances of Saxon and Norman periods. (Box 34, Folder M105)
  - Hol 2 p; the .manorial system in England. (Box 34, Folder M118)
  - Hol 10 p; EH; sources of knowledge on manorial systems. (Box 34, Folder M119)
  - Hol 4 p EH; manorial systems - 11th to 13th centuries. (Box 34, Folder M114)
  - Hol 17 p; EH; Black Death. (Box 34, Folder M108)
  - Hol 1 p; Guild origins. (Box 34, Folder M179)
  - Hol 16 p; EH; later development of towns and guilds. (Box 34, Folder M109)
  - Hol 1 p; English borrowings. (Box 34, Folder M177)
  - Hol 17 p; EH; commercial policy of Edward I and Edward III. (Box 34, Folder M112)
  - Hol 7 p; EH; English trading companies. (Box 34, Folder M107)
  - Hol 3 p; EH; Mercantilism. (Box 34, Folder M125)
  - hol 28 p; EH; colonial system and mercantilism (with bibliography) (Box 34, Folder M115)
  - Hol 5 p; EH; Mercantilism (with bibliography). (Box 34, Folder M106)
  - Hol 11 p; EH; enclosures of 15th and 16th centuries. (Box 34, Folder M110)
  - Hol 3 D; money economy and theory of money in 1549. (Box 34, Folder M330)
  - Hol 7 p; SH; Elizabethan legislation. (Box 34, Folder M113)
  - Hol 49 p; EH; social results of industrial and agricultural revolutions (with bibliography). (Box 34, Folder M121)
  - hol 2 p; EH; assignments (Box 34, Folder M123)
  - Hol 1 p; outline of history of money economy. (Box 34, Folder M178)
  - Mimeograph 27 p; outline of history of European banking. (Box 34, Folder M102)
  - [1921 or 1923]; hol 2 p; "Businessman and Economics". (Box 34, Folder M104)
  - [1923 or 1924]; typed 34 p; "Money Economy and Economic Efficiency". (Box 34, Folder M126)
  - [between 1923 and 1929]; carbon 2 p; excerpts copy 1 p; "World Monetary problem" talk on price stabilization to Joint Session of AEA and American Association for Labor Legislation. (Box 34, Folder M174)
  - [1925 or 1926?] carbon; 9 p; outline of introductory economics course on money economy. (Box 34, Folder M103)
  - [after 1941]; typed and hol 5 p; "Notes on Marginal Analysis"; initialed AFB [Burns] (Box 34, Folder M329)
  - WCM notes on his reading; undated:
    - Hol 1 p; contents of E. Allanison [?]; Report on Bimetalism in Europe. (Box 34, Folder M130)
    - Hol 3 p; abstract of C. Andrews: history of Mark theory. (Box 34, Folder M127)
    - Hol 11 p; abstracts and quotes by Aristotle: money. (Box 34, Folder M52)
    - Hol 4 p; abstract of W. Ashley: origin of English manor. (Box 34, Folder M128)
    - Hol 1 p; abstracts and statistics by Bonmation and H. Hayes: monetary reform 1696. (Box 34, Folder M53)
    - hol 2 p; abstract of S. Breckenridge: Legal Tender (Box 34, Folder M81)
    - hol 36 p; abstract of K. Bucher: Essays in Economic History (Box 34, Folder M54)
    - hol 1 p; abstract of W. Carlile.: evolution of English gold standard (Box 34, Folder M55)
    - Printed 1 p; review of W. Cole: The American Hope. (Box 34, Folder M56)
    - Hol 1 p; quotes by J. Commons: earnings of organized labor 1897-1903. (Box 34, Folder M57)
    - Typed 8 p; quotes by M. Copeland: making money and goods, money economy and economic reform. (Box 34, Folder M164)
    - Hol 13 p; abstract of A. Courtois: French finances 1870-71. (Box 34, Folder M58)
    - hol 4 p; quotes by Cunningham: 13th century use of money on manors, estate management, bookkeeping (Box 34, Folder M59)
    - Hol 20 p; quotes and abstracts of M. Decker: Essay on the Causes of the Decline in Foreign Trade. (Box 34, Folder M60)
    - Hol 15 p; abstract of A. De Viti de Marco: Moneta e Prezzi. (Box 34, Folder M82)
    - hol 6 p; abstract of A. Doren: the guild merchant (Box 34, Folder M61)
    - Hol 14 p; abstract of A. Ecengreuth [?]; medieval coining and monetary policy, prerogative of coinage. (Box 34, Folder M62)
    - hol 91 p; abstract of R. Ehrenberg: Fuggers and other moneyed men, Florentians and other Italians, Genoese and Dutch and Spanish business men, money powers in 16th century, Antwerp, rise of Lyons, 16th century bourses, 1557-66 crisis, struggles and crises 1566-77, from Bas Zerbalter der Fugger, Geld Kapital und Credit. (Box 34, Folder M63)
    - Hol 1 p; reference to W. Fite: "Theory of Democracy". (Box 34, Folder M64)
    - Hol 7 p; abstracts of E. Foldes: "Beitrage zur Freage", "Beitrage zur statistik", "Literatur zur Freage". (Box 34, Folder M65)
    - Hol 2 p; abstract of Forbes: "World's Rising Production of Gold and its Influence on Commodity prices." (Box 34, Folder M66)
    - Hol 11 p; life and work of T. Gresham (J. Burgon). (Box 34, Folder M67)
    - hol 13 p; abstract, of C. Gross: The Guild Merchant (Box 34, Folder M126)
    - Hol 24 p; abstract of H. Grueber: Handbook of the Coins of Great Britain and Ireland in the British Museum. (Box 34, Folder M68)
    - hol 20 p; abstract of J. Harris; Essay upon Money and Coins (Box 34, Folder M69)
    - hol 14 p; abstract of W. Hasback History of the English Agricultural laborer (Box 34, Folder M70)
    - Hol 4 p; abstract of Hearnes: pepper loan of 1640-41, assessment of wages 1562 act, middleman and domestic system, business organization in 17th century. (Box 34, Folder M71)
    - Hol 3 p; abstract of T. Hertzka: Wahrung und Handel. (Box 34, Folder M74)
    - hol 2 p; abstract of B. Hildebrand: (Box 34, Folder M72)
    - Hol 28 p; quotes by Keller: ancient Greece. (Box 34, Folder M182)
    - hol 9 p; abstract of H. Koch (Box 35, Folder M73)
    - hol 39 p; abstract of K. Kramer: Das Papiergeld in Oesterreich seit 1848 (see M74) (Box 35, Folder M73)
    - hol 52 p; abstracts of J.L. Laughlin: History of Bimetalism (Box 35, Folder M75)
    - Hol 13 p; abstract of J. Law: value, origin of money, silver, own schemes, Scotland, land bank, Première Mémoire. (Box 35, Folder M76)
    - Hol 8 p; abstracts of G. Leonhardt: Austrian monetary history 1848-66; bibliography. (Box 35, Folder M77)
    - hol 33 p; abstracts of W. Lesigang: Austrian monetary history (Box 35, Folder M77)
    - hol 17 p; abstracts of W. Lexis: Austrian paper money (see M77) (Box 35, Folder M78)
    - hol 24 p; abstracts and quotes by J. Locke: "Considerations of the Consequences of Lowering Interest", "Observations on Coining of Silver Money", "Further Considerations of Raising the Value of Silver Money." (Box 35, Folder M79)
    - Hol 27 p; abstract of A. Loria; Studi sul Valori della Moneta. (Box 35, Folder M80)
    - Hol 12 p; abstracts of H. Macleod: Theory of Credit. (Box 35, Folder M83)
    - hol 1 p; abstract of C. Menger: (Box 35, Folder M84)
    - Hol 3 p; abstract of M. Muhlman: Stocks of Gold in the United States. (Box 35, Folder M85)
    - hol 25 p; abstract of A. Nagel: (Box 35, Folder M86)
    - hol 5 p; abstract of P. Pacher: (Box 35, Folder M86)
    - Hol 1 p; reference to E.T. Powell: Evolution of the Money Market. (Box 35, Folder M185)
    - Hol 1 p; abstract of L. Price: prices in 16th and 17th centuries. (Box 35, Folder M87)
    - Hol 1 p; abstract of R. Prothers: corn laws. (Box 35, Folder M88)
    - Hol 10 p; abstract of Ruding: coinage history. (Box 35, Folder M89)
    - Typed 1 p; quote by S. Slichter: competition and money making. (Box 35, Folder M192)
    - Hol 3 p; abstract and quotes by Vi. Shaw: Mercantilist maxims, gold-silver ratio and coinage before 1492. (Box 35, Folder M90)
    - Hol 7 p; abstracts of Sieveking: medieval barter and expenses and investment, Commenda, Venetian trade and banking, early companies. (Box 35, Folder M91)
    - Hol 6 p; statistics by A.; gold and silver production 1492-1875. (Box 35, Folder M92)
    - Hol 16 p; abstract of T. Tooke: currency principle, History of Prices. (Box 35, Folder M93)
    - Hol 16 p; abstract of A. Toynbee: Lectures on the Industrial Revolution in England. (Box 35, Folder M94)
    - Hol 6 p; abstract of Unwin: 12th and l7th Century London oligarchy and early guilds, guild prevalence. (Box 35, Folder M95)
    - Hol 23 p; abstract of R. Vaughan: Discourse on Coin and Coining. (Box 35, Folder M96)
    - Hol 23 p; abstracts of A. Wagner: Russian paper money, inconvertible paper money theory (see M75). (Box 35, Folder M98)
    - hol 15 p; abstract of G. Wiebe: (Box 35, Folder M99)
    - Hol 22 p; abstracts by Wieser: Austrian paper money (see M84). (Box 35, Folder M99)
    - hol 3 p; abstract of A. Youngman: Standard Oil, and Morgan, Harriman Kuhn-Loeb groups (Box 35, Folder M100)
    - hol 2 p; abstracts of S. Ross, L. Merriam, Fetter, J.B. Clark: money as standard of deferred payment (Box 35, Folder M97)
    - hol p; abstracts of Montesquieu, J. Stewart, Hume, Arthur Young, J. Wheatley: quantity theory of money (Box 35, Folder M101)
    - hol 2 p; abstracts of Bucher, Cunningham, E. Meyer: economic life of Greece and Rome (Box 35, Folder M181)
    - Hol 31 p; abstracts of Rodbertus, Bucher, Beloch, E. Meyer, Diehl, Lamprecht: economic development of ancient times. (Box 35, Folder M204)
    - hol 12 p; abstract of E. Simcox [?], J. Hittall: ancient Egypt (Box 35, Folder M183)
    - Hol 1 p; notes for historical material on money economy; bibliography and notes [for book?] (Box 35, Folder M184)
    - Hol 1 p; references to Bernheim and Langlois: psychology and history study. (Box 35, Folder M189)
  - Following are WCM notes and Ms for proposed book on the money economy.
    - Hol 1 p; Chapter I - outline - growth of money economy. (Box 35, Folder M332)
    - hol 1 p; Chapter I; money economy and capitalism - Somber, Hobson, Veblen (Box 35, Folder M333)
    - hol 2 p; Chapter II; "Development of the Money Economy"; references to E. Meyer, L. Friedlander, L. Magnus, J. Frieze. (Box 35, Folder M334)
    - Hol 1 p; Chapter XI; "Evaluation of the Money Economy". (Box 35, Folder M335)
    - hol 37 p; collection of notes and mss accompanying above book material; on: (Box 35, Folder M336)
    - Hedonism (Box 35)
    - Economic theory and money economy (Box 35)
    - Money and economic theory (Box 35)
    - Economic rationality (Box 35)
    - Consumers' surplus (Marshall, Patten) (Box 35)
    - levels of analysis (Box 35)
    - Valuation consistency (J.B. Clark, Edgeworth) (Box 35)
    - Pecuniary logic and interests and material wellbeing (Box 35)
    - Medieval economics history (Box 35)
    - Institutions (Veblen) (Box 35)
    - Critique and problems of economic theory (Box 35)
    - Method (Box 35)
    - Utility (Box 35)
    - Money economy and conduct (Box 35)
    - Economic laws (J. Dewey) (Box 35)
    - Fabians and Benthamites (Box 35)
    - Pure and institutional theory (Box 35)
    - Clipping on national (Box 35)
    - Bankruptcy (Box 35)
- Series VII: [N] National Planning, (1 Box: Box 15)
  - 1931 Jun 5; carbon Ms 3 p& clipping; draft of WGM views on W.R. Hearst public works proposals; New York Herald Tribune account. (Box 15)
  - 1932 Jan [?]; carbon Us 5p; prefatory note to O.T. Mallery's book on planning and public works. (Box 15)
  - 1932 Oct 3; hol 12 p; "Laissez-faire and Central Planning"; talk to Oxford University Liberal Club. (Box 15)
  - 1932 Nov 17; carbon Ms 8 p; "The University and Economic Changes"; address to New York University Centennial Conference. (Box 15)
  - 1933 Jun 23; hol 8 p; "Trend of Economic Organization in the U.S."; talk to Section K of the AAAS. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Mar 17; hol 11 p; copy 8 p; "Social Planning"; talk to Bureau of Educational Experiments. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep [?]; printed 4 p; program of WCM Hitchcock Lectures at University of California. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 3; hol 13 p; outline of Hitchcock lecture no. l, 3p. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 5; holl2 p; Hitchcock lecture no.2. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 7; hol 17 p; Hitchcock lecture no. 3 (originally no.4). (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 11; hol 8 p; Hitchcock lecture no.4 (originally no.5). (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 12; hol 1 p; talk on New Deal policy; at University of California. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 13; hol 16 p; Hitchcock lecture no.5. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 17; hol 18 p; Hitchcock lecture no. 6. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep [19]; hol 12 p; Hitchcock lecture no. 7. (incorrectly dated Sep 17) (Box 15)
  - l934, Sep 24; hol 12 p; Hitchcock lecture no. 8. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Sep 26; hol 15 p; Hitchcock lecture no. 9. (Box 15)
  - 1934 Nov 29; typed ms 17 p; "National Planning"; script of radio broadcast with L. Tyson. (Box 15)
  - 1935 Feb 18; hol 12 p; carbon is 23 p; manuscript and transcript of WCM Messenger lecture no. 1. at Cornell University; with introduction by L. Farrand. (Box 15)